Are you ready? Yeah? Okay, here we go.
大家准备好了吗？好了？好，那我们开始。
First question for you, who experienced some difficulties
第一个问题，当把DDD这个概念
to grasp DDD concept at the very beginning
运用到项目或者代码里的时候，
while it's the time to put it into your project or into your code?
你们有谁遇到了困难？
Yeah ok. So you're not alone. I have to confess
好吧，看来大家都有这样的困惑。我确实
I see a lot of talk about DDD.
看到过很多关于DDD的讨论。
And I
我
tried to apply on legacy code.
也试过把DDD用在遗留代码上。
So that's why we've made this session.
这就是我们举行这个会议的原因。
Absolutely. At this time here we will mostly talk about technical patterns.
没错。这次我们主要讨论技术模式。
And most likely talking about where and how to put your domain experience of your business
主要讲一下怎样把你的领域知识放到
into your code.
代码中。
Much more than strategical pattern. We'll talk a little bit about it.
我们也会稍微涉及一些战略模式，不过不会仅限于此。
But it's rather technical.
但是整个会议呢，还是比较
on the entire session.
偏向技术的。
Let's introduce ourself maybe before we move?
我们进行下一步之前先介绍一下自己吧？
Oh yeah. So I'm Bruno Boucard. I'm coming from Paris and I'm a coach.
嗯好。我是Bruno Boucard。是来自巴黎的讲师。
I'm teaching TDD, BDD and DDD.
我教TDD，BDD和DDD。
And I'm in charge of
我现在负责
BDD meet up in Paris.
巴黎的BDD会议。
Ok, my name is Thomas Pierrain.
我是Thomas Pierrain。
I'm working software since 18 years. I'm also co-organize the DDD Paris meetup.
我18岁以来就从事软件工作。我也是巴黎DDD会议的组织者之一。
I'm kind of opposite, by use cases and
我更倾向于
problems based.
基于问题。
Cause I think we jump too much too soon into the solution based.
因为我认为我们太快进入基于解决方案了。
All our ??? and stuff like that, all solutions.
我们周围的好多都是基于解决方案的。
So this is one of my obsession.
这是我的一个发现。
Ok we have some gifts
好，我们为大家准备了
for you.
一些礼物。
So we have two books.
这有两本书。
??? The blue one and the Refactoring by Martin Fowler.
蓝色的这本，还有Martin Fowler的重构。
So to win those books you would have to tweet as hell during the session.
如果想赢得这些书，大家得在会议期间多发推文。
Using the #DDDEU.
并加上#DDDEU。
We have a referee here
我们这有一个裁判。
So he will have a look at that hash tag. And the most
他到时候会去看这个标签。最有趣的
funny tweet or you can record, you can take picture, you can do jokes about us or about you, whatever
推文将会获奖。大家可以录像，可以照相，可以开我们的玩笑，也可以开你们自己的玩笑，怎样都行。
and John will tell us the two winners at the end of the session. All right? Cool.
John会在会议最后公布最终的两个获奖人。好吗？
Our domain for today will be train.
我们今天来说说火车领域。
Train is kind of large. Actually so we will focus more on the seat reservation optimazation.
火车领域其实还挺大的。我们今天主要关注怎么来优化座位预定。
Here is the model of a train. The train which has three coaches. Coach A, coach B, and coach C.
这是一个火车模型。这个火车有三个车厢，A，B和C。
Which has some
橙色的代表
seats already reserved in the orange.
已经被预定的座位。
Empty seats are in white.
白色的代表空座位。
And here we are asking 6 seats
现在我们要预定6个座位
to be reserved there in the train in blue. This is a simple model but that may help to understand something。
蓝色的这6个。这是个比较简单的模型，这个图也有助我们的理解。
something. Okay?
好吧。
We have two business rules for today for the system. The first one is
今天我们的系统有两个业务准则。第一个是
We should not reserve more than 70% of the entire train capacity.
我们最多只能预定火车总座位的70%。
Okay this is the first business rule.The second business rule is
好这是第一个业务规准则。第二个是
When I want to reserve, I want all my seats in the same coach.
当我预定座位时，所有的座位要在同一个车厢。
We don't want to split families and friends
谁也不想家人朋友坐在
between coaches. Right?
不同的车厢。对吧？
Simple.
就这么简单。
We are taking those rules from Emily Bache's Train Reservation.
我们是从Emily Bache火车预订那里得到这些准则的。
And we've put some crappy code on top of that but... ok
我们这还有一些用来实现这些规则的代码。
Our domain expert couldn't manage to be with us in Amsterdam today but we talked a lot with him before
我们的领域专家今天不能跟我们一起来到阿马斯特丹，不过前几周，
previous weeks.
我们和他谈了很多。
So he talked a lot about rain
他谈了很多火车相关的话题。
He talked about train ID or identifier. He talked about seats.
他谈了火车ID、火车座位，
Coaches.
火车车厢之类的。
Reservation attempts and whether or not these reservation attemps are fulfilled.
还谈了预定，还有这些预定有没有成功。
And you know there are also to book. If I'm to book,
如果我准备订票，还得有订票功能。
Booking reference we have explained what it is.
我们之前已经解释了什么是订票单据。
Reservation, reservation failure.
什么是预定，什么是预定失败。
That's the word from the expert. Yeah you know the session we have, those words
这是专家的用词。对，我们之前的交流，
kind of
用的就是这些词。
So we will work for a start-up company which name is Train Train. They provide
我们将会为一个名为Train Train的初创公司工作。他们提供
seat reservation service which is basically web API.
座位预定服务，是个web API。
And this web API to do its work, he has to rely on the
这个web API还依赖于
external backends provided by external companies
其他公司提供的后端支持。
So in fact it's SNCF
也就是SNCF。
So the first backends provided by SNCF,
SNCF提供的第一个后端支持
which is extermal to our company, it's Train Data
是Train Data。
Basically it's a
它就是一个
train topology service.
火车拓扑服务。
Meaning we provide a train event for you.
也就是说我们给他一个火车事件，
And we get back the topology of the train meaning
我们可以就得到火车拓扑，比如
all the coaches and for every coach, all the seats and for every seat, whether or not it's available
所有的车厢，每一个车厢里的所有座位，每一个座位是可以预定的状态，
or already reserved.
还是已经被预定了。
Okay. Quantity
对，还有数量。
Second one is the booking reference. This is a kind of tricky one because... not tricky
第二个是订票单据。这个有点麻烦...也不麻烦
When you buy a ticket, you have an ID
当你买完票，你的火车票上就会有一个ID。
on your train ticket. This is the idea actually. Yeah. But this is a service that only provide a unique identifier.
就是这个意思。对。这就是一个只提供ID的服务。
We call it
我们用它
book anything with that.
来订票。
All we can do is to get a unique identifier
我们用它只是
to play with.
得到一个ID
And once seat reservation service on the left will have train topology, find available seats,
当左边的预定服务拿到火车拓扑后，我们就能找到可选的座位，
then,
然后
Getting a booking reference, we actually book
可以拿到一个订票单据，我们其实是
the reservation
通过
through the national train operator service
国家列车运营服务来订票的。
through the last train booking service.
就是通过最下面的这个火车订票服务。
All right? In terms of we are kind of down streams. We are a tiny start-up in that
好吧？我们是一个初创公司，在这个刚开放的市场中
open market that hasn't been opened recently. So these are the back-end provided by the national train.
还处于下游。这些后端的服务是国家列车运营服务提供的。
Is it ok for all of you?
到现在大家有什么问题吗？
We will continue.
那我们继续。
Maybe Bruno we can do a demo of the web API
Bruno现在可以演示一下Web API。
It will take a few
需要
seconds to
几秒钟
switch.
才能转换屏幕。
So
嗯
I use postman
我用的是postman，
where you can see the url to call the web API.
你可以看到我调用Web API时的url。
And we can see the body
我们还能看到请求体
The payload is with two fields.
有两个值。
Train_id is the identifier of the train.
Train_id是火车的ID。
And the number_of_seats requested.
还有请求的座位数量number_of_seats。
Ok
好
So if you post.
如果你发送请求。
Yeah.
没错。
Take a while.
需要等一会。
Still loading. Okay and we have a answer.
还在加载。好现在我们得到了响应。
The answer.
这就是响应。
The first is the train_id.
第一个是train_id。
Okay?
对吧？
Second one is a booking reference.
第二个是订票单据。
Allocated by service as I said before。
是通过我们之前说的那个服务得到的。
And the list of seats
然后我们得到了
We get back.
座位的列表。
Okay. So basically that's quite simple way to interact with our system. Yeah.
好，我们的系统还挺简单的，对。
Okay. And basically we have a problem. And this is reason why we are here today.
不过我们有一个问题，这也是为什么我们今天在这里。
Train Train start-up, called us because they face recurrent penalties,
Train Train公司找到我们，说一直都在面临着一个问题。
Excess of penalties by the national train service.
国家列车运营服务给他们带来的问题。
Why?
什么问题呢？
Every call
每一次调用
You made on all those back-ends, you pay fees. So that means that start-up the Train Train start-up.
后端服务的时候，都是收费的。这对Train Train这个初创公司意味着
Every time you call one of those web API is charged from these.
每次调用这些web API都要钱。
So they are expected
他们知道这些调用是要钱的，
to do so. But,
但是
they think they are paying too much.
他们觉得还是太贵了。
So they asked us to have a look at the code.
因此他们让我们来看一下代码。
And to see
来看看
what may be the reason and can we troubleshoot and fix
到底是为什么，看看我们能不能找到它，如果有什么要修复的话，
if we have something to fix
看看能不能修复。
Okay? But before touching any legacy code, if you are... Bruno and I, what would you recommend
好吧？但是在我们着手遗留代码之前，如果你...
大家建议我和Bruno
us to do?
应该先干什么？
(Test?) Test, yes absolutely.
（测试？）测试，没错。
In fact, this is the reason why we miss the keynote. We have a bit test on this this morning.
事实上，这就是我们错过主题演讲的原因。今天早上我们对此进行了一些测试。
Discovering the code in trying to highlight
查看代码，试着凸显
all those business rules. So we've made so far 3 exception tests.
那些业务准则。到现在为止我们写了三个测试。
First on is a happy pass. We have a train with only one coach
第一个测试通过了。我们建了一个只有一个车厢
with 10 seats. And we want allocate or reserve 3 seats.
一共10个座的火车。我们想预定3个座位。
And as you can see that's exactly what I do with postman. And exactly the same answer.
你看这就是我用postman做的，响应也都一样。
Simple happy pass. Ok.
通过。
Second one is the
第二个测试是
Yeah this is the first business rule.  We can't exceed 70%,
对这是第一个业务准则。我们对预定不能超过
for reservation , in all the train. And if we ask 2 seats,
所有座位的70%。如果我们现在想预定2个座位，
and you can see I already have 6 seats reserved,
现在我们已经订出去了6个座位了，
Here.
这里
Because I applied the rule,
因为这个准则，
So 70% is 7 seats in the train you can sit. Exactly. So the way to repond an error
70%也就是只有7个座位可以被预定。没错。所以是这么响应
is this one
这个错误的。
I get the train ID but the booking reference is empty.
我能得到火车的ID，但是订票单据是空的。
And the list of seats are empty.
而且座位列表也是空的。
This is how Train Train is telling us, no
用这种方式，Train Train告诉我们，我们没有
reservation has been made for you.
预定任何座位。
Ok.
好。
And the third test was... test highlighting the all seats must be in the same coach please.
第三个测试是...所有的预定必须是在同一个车厢里。
The second business rule.
这是第二个业务准则。
And in that case we found a bug. We found a bug because we asked
这种情况下我们找到了bug，因为我们这有
here we have a train with two coaches. And one is almost full.
一个两节车厢的火车。一节车厢基本上满了。
The other is completely free. And when we asked 2 seats,
另一节车厢完全是空的。当我们想订2个座位时，
Actually we get here. One seat in coach A and one seat in coach B, which was unexpected because
我们得到的是这个结果。两个车厢一边一个座位，这不是我们想要的，
we don't want to split families and friends.
因为我们让家人朋友分开坐。
So we're thinking about that. Bruno was saying that
我们正在考虑的这个问题。Bruno说
it may explain something related to this phase.
这结果也许解释了一些事。
You have some ideas about what may explain the extra phase.
大家可能想到了这个结果会导致什么。
Imagine you use
试想你用
the website.
网站订票
You call the service.
你调用了后端的服务。
And you prepare a trip
你准备跟家人
With your family or your
或者你的女朋友，男朋友
girlfriend boyfriend.
一起旅行。
What happened? （Maybe you want to cancel your reservation because you cannot sit with your firend.）
会发生什么？（也许你就会取消这个预定了，因为你不能跟朋友坐一起了。）
Yeah. Exactly. The answer is to cancel.
没错，这会导致人们取消预定。
Because I'm not pleased to have 2 seats in 2 different coaches. We cancel maybe retry it.
因为我可不想俩座位分别在俩车厢。我也许会取消了再订一次试试。
Cancel retry, cancel retry, at the end of the day I will switch to another provider.
取消重新订，再取消，再订，最后可能我就会换一个别的地方订票了。
I will left Train Train.
就不用Train Train了。
Poor experience.
因为用户体验太差。
But it may explain that because every time every attempt will be charged actually.
这也解释了为什么Train Train会觉得服务很贵，因为每一次预定都会被收费。
So that was our hypothesis.
这是我们的假设。
And we discussed it with domain expert and he said, yeah,
我们跟领域专家讨论过。他说，是啊
maybe a new answer, please
也许得找个新的方案，拜托
guys can you please fix that bug.
你们要修好这个bug啊。
So we are here to fix that bug all together. And we will ask you to help us in the journey.
所以，我们现在要一起修好这个bug。我们也会在这个过程中寻求大家的帮助。
So what would you recommend to fix that bug?
大家现在有什么建议吗？
What would be your strategy?
你们的策略是什么？（预定的那个服务是从Train Data那个服务拿数据吗？）
We are the train reservation service on the left on the Orange. Here, let me...ok
我们是左边橙色的这个火车票预定服务。这个，我来...
We are only working on that seat reservation in the yellow.
我们现在只管黄色的这个座位预定。
These are dependencies. We don't have leverage on that actually. (Are you the only cosumer for these)
这些都是依赖。我们其实没法控制。（是只有我们用这些服务吗？）
No we compete with other companies. We are start-up and we compete with other companies.
不，我们和其他公司一起竞争。我们是一个初创公司，我们要跟别人竞争。
We need some information from those two and we need to set and to comfirm
我们需要从那俩服务获取信息，我们还得设置信息、确认信息、
and to book
还要订票，
to make transaction with that guy
用它来交易。
So
所以
That's kind of interaction we have.
这就是我们能做的操作。
So it's time for the strategy what would you recommend? (Writing tests?)
那现在还有什么建议吗？（写测试？）
Write tests.
写测试。
Yeah write tests.
没错，写测试。
So actually we already wrote 2 tests so that highlight the bug. So we will have to fix that test. Ok?
其实我们已经写好了2个测试，来凸显这个bug。我们要修这个bug了。
So let's dive into the code.
那我们看看代码吧。
Bruno has
Bruno已经
set breakpoints
设了几个断点
We can call it here. Yeah absolutely. Just a minute.
我们可以在这调用一下。没错，要等一小会儿。
It's launching the bug
现在正在触发这个bug。
So here if you
这块，
just slide to the left side of the screen
稍微向左移一下屏幕。
It's a C# code. It's a asp.net code API.
这是个C#代码，用的是asp.net的API。
It's simple for those who are doing java spring boot. It's simple for... When we request that post on networks
这对于用Java Spring Boot的人来说比较简单。当我们用那个名字
with that name
请求网络服务时
We get that call back
我们可以得到响应。
And it's a ReservationRequestDto we receive.
我们得到了ReservationRequestDto。
Just to have a look at the Dto. It's very simple, exactly the payload of the json.
看一下这个Dto，这个很简单，跟JSON完全一样。
Absolutely.
没错。
And so after all that, we installed that, if you can slide to the left, thank you. So we installed that
然后我们安装了它，往左移一下屏幕，谢谢。你看我们安装了
webTicketManager which it seems to be the entry point of the system and we call reserve
webTicketManager，是这个系统的入口。我们会调用
method on it,
它上面的预定方法。
providing train id and the number of seat requested.
把train_id和预定的座位数当作参数。
Ok so
好了
This is what we have test so far
这就是我们目前的测试。
If we have a look at the tests. These are failing.
我们可以看一下这些测试，这些挂了。
We have 3 tests.
我们一共有3个测试。
It's like kind of exception tests. We consider these items as black bugs.
这就像是异常测试，我们把这些当作black bug。
And we sent some requests and we checked the
如果我们发送这些请求，然后查看
json.
一下json数据
The last one is the test
最后一个测试，
demonstrate the problem. Ok?
我们就可以看出这个问题。是吧？
So wait. We have a tool, it's name is ???  We see every time we change
稍等，我们有一个工具。每当我们做改变的时候，
something, we type something, we change the code. It will run the test in background, execute it,
我们输入一些东西，改变代码，它会在后台自动跑测试。
and provide us a feedback loop with a colored arrow on the margin.
然后左边会有有颜色的箭头，是给我们反馈。
So green is fine and red is
绿色代表没问题，红色
there's a problem. And there's an arrow in Red.
代表有问题。这就有个红箭头。
Bruno, if you...
Bruno，你来...
Yeah I will show. Have another view of the error.
好我来展示。看看这个错误。
Basically it's the problem. We are expecting to have
这问题是，我们本来想要2个座位，
2 seats in 1B and 2B. And actually we get
1B和2B，但是我们得到的却是
10A and 1B. So this is the bug we discuss earlier.
10A和1B。这是我们之前就讨论过的bug。
Ok everyone?
对吧？
I think it would be a good thing to stop to have another view of what the Reserve method is doing.
我觉得现在最好停一下，我们再看看这个Reserve方法在干什么。
I'll just align the code for you.
我帮你找一下代码。
Let's have a first overview. We discovered that this morning so we will have
我们先看一下。我们今天早上的时候看过了一次，所以
a little bit more knowledge about it. So I will try to help you to
我们可能更熟悉这段代码。我们会帮大家
to have an overview.
过一遍这代码。
First we ??? a list of available seats. That should be
首先我们有一个可选座位的列表。这应该是
probably the result of the method.
这个方法的结果。
Then we call a get train on a trainDataService.
然后我们调用trainDataService上的get train方法。
And we get something like we call jsonTrain. Maybe is a json topology we will see it after.
我们就得到了jsonTrain这个数据。这也许是json拓扑，我们以后再看。
Then we install a train. A train installs of ??? json topology.
然后我们就得到了train，一个火车拓扑。
And after that train installed, we do some business rules here and there. So here,
得到train之后，我们需要添加一些业务准则。
if the number of seat already reserved in the train plus the number of seats I'm requesting
如果被预定的座位数加上我想预定的座位数，
is below,
低于
is below something like GetMaxRes, let me check.
低于GetMaxRes这个数，我看一下，
Should be some percentage or something like that. Yeah, 70%.
应该是个百分数吧。对，70%。
Ok.
好。
70% of the overall train capacity.
火车总座位数的70%。
So if
如果
I respect the first business rule, I continue.
我们符合这个业务准则，那么我就可以继续。
I continue. The numberOfReserv seems to be an accumulator variable here
继续之后，numberOfReserv感觉像是个累加变量。
And we tried to find some available seats.
我们想找到可选的座位。
An availble seat in that system is the one that the BookingRef is empty.
可选座位指的是系统里面BookingRef为空的座位。
We have a property and if it's empty string,
我们这有个属性，如果它为空的话，
that means that seat is available
就代表这个座位可选。
And then we can add it
然后我们就可以把它加入到
into the list.
座位列表里。
The list that we will return at the end of the method
就是方法最后我们要返回的列表。
Is it okay for you so for?
到现在都还跟得上吧大家？
Then we have a kind of stupid forEach. We haven't seen that in years ago.
然后这还有一些愚蠢的forEach，我们几年都没有看到过这个了。
Oh then what do we have yes if we can't
如果我们没有那么多可被预定的座位
find the number of seat requested, what do we do? We get the answer, you know,
怎么办？我们会得到一个响应。
the result that is saying that you can't even reserve.
告诉你不可以预定了。
Remember, it's a failing message.
这个可是一个失败的消息啊。
If it work, that when we call the bookingReferenceService, the one in the middle on the right side.
如果座位预定好了，我们会调用bookingReferenceService，就是在右边中间部分的这个。
And call GetBookingReference.
然后调用GetBookingReference。
Then we
然后我们
assign a booking reference to every one of the available seat that we have found.
给每一个可预定的座位附上一个订票收据。
So far
到现在为止
We have a bunch of accumulators here.
我们有很多的累加器。
And then, again, it's
然后这里，又有一个
pretty much the same if. If you look at...Yeah it seems similar. No the first one is negative.
跟之前基本一样的if。你看之前的。对确实像的。不对，第一个条件是不等。
Not really same. But,
不完全一样。
if it's still ok, oh we use the cache? Yeah. Interesting.
如果条件还满足的话...哦我们这还用了cache？是啊，有意思。
We will see that...why, okay?
我们等会再看看这是为什么，好吧？
And then what do we... Actually this is the one that is making the booking, you know.
然后我们会干什么...这其实是在订票。
Transaction actually.
其实就是交易。
It will be the external web API we call to book a seat.
订票的话我们调用的是一个外部的web API。
If I
如果我
enter that,
进入这个的话
let me check,
我看一下
here the implemetation.
这是它的实现。
Yeah basically we call a web API.
对我们就是调用了一个web API。
Real Interesting.
有点意思。
And it seems that if we don't have any kind of exception here,
如果这没什么异常的话，
what do we do? We return the answer.
我们会返回一个数据。
And the answer is the one dumping the list of seats
返回值就是到目前为止我们找到的
we have found so far. Okay?
座位列表。都没什么问题吧？
And the case here, what was it? Yes, in the case of the train capacity limit
这里在干什么来着？哦对，如果预定座位数超过
has been exceeded,
火车总座位数的话，
we return the empty... you can't reserve anything in that train. It's a failure.
我们返回一个空值。你就不能预定了。预定失败了。
Ok for everyone of you?
对吧？
We will make a few review working on it. But,
我们之后还会回过头再看一下这里，不过
do you have some
现在大家有什么
feedback about that so far？
疑问吗？
(Why are you using string concatenation to create json?)
（你们为什么用字符串连接来创建json？）
Why are we using string concatenation to create json?
我们为什么用字符串连接来创建json？
Actually this is not our code.
其实这也不是我们自己写的代码。
As a declarer. This is a customer we discover this morning. So yes, but this is a good remark, why do we
先声明一下，这是客户的代码，今天早上才成为我们客户的。不过你说的很对。我们为什么
append a json here in the middle of something that, it's expected to be some kind of
要在这里加json呢？这里应该是有一些
business logic.
业务逻辑吧。
(Prove it with a github link.) We don't even use git in that project. You know.
（用github link证明一下你刚才说的呗？） 我们在这个项目里都没用到git。
So I can't do that. (Maybe I think the business logic is quite intermixed all togather in one function?)
我没法证明啊。（我觉得是不是应该把业务逻辑放在一个方法里啊？）
Yeah, you are right.
没错。
Yeah absolutely. Yeah.
对，确实是。
That is a strategy we will try to apply with you. We try to discover
我们以后可以试试你的这个建议。我们会试着
the domain concept through this code.
通过代码去了解火车领域的概念。
And we try to figure out how can we improve that because so far there's something that's really bother me.
我们试图弄清楚如何才能改进这个代码，因为到目前为止，有些东西真的挺让我烦恼的。
We were talking about the domain expert
我们刚才说的那个领域专家，
talking with us with tons of concepts.
跟我们讲理很多的概念。
Can you see apart the train, and the
除了火车的概念
concept of seat, do you see any
座位的概念，你们还能看出
other concept as well?
其他的概念吗？
There's something missing. (Coach isn't explained. )
有些东西是缺失的。（这没有车厢的概念。）
Yeah. The concept of coach is completely missing here.
没错，车厢的概念完全缺失了。
And other stuff? (Reservation?)
其他的呢？（预定的概念？）
Reservation, absolutely. No reservation. No reservation at time so far.
预定，没错。到现在为止，没有预定的概念。
So, who have experienced code like this?
大家谁之前有看过类似这样的代码？
In this case. Some of you.
看来有人遇到过啊。
So we are not alone. So the idea here, for us will be to have a kind of way of
看来并不是只有我们遇到了这个问题。对所有在座的人来说，今天我们要找出一个方式
improving it.
来改进这个代码。
Because,
因为
since we don't have any kind of coach here,
因为现在我们这没有指导，
the strategy for us to fix the bug would be to make it
我们来修bug的策略就是先看懂它。
But before that,
但在那之前，
there's so much crappy thing and like that.
这有好多糟糕的代码啊。
So let's clean,
我们先清理一下。
first clean the deck? Yeah.
先Clean the deck？是的。
Do you know the name clean the deck?
你们知道Clean the deck是什么吗？
The expression clean the deck? No?
Clean the deck这种说法？不知道？
Clean the deck
is the first phase when you discover a code,
是你检测代码的第一步
because you need to be more confident before
因为在做深度重构之前，你必须
to apply deep refactoring.
让自己更有信心。
It's a way to discover, fix a little
这是检测代码的一种方式，从小的地方去修复代码，
names of the variables, for example,
就比如变量名字啊。
And after,
这之后，
get into the program. Yeah, it's a way to prepare our mental model in your head.
再继续编程。是的，这就是我们在脑海里准备一个心理模型的方式。
So come back from the beginning, so clean the deck, you will have another view,
好那我们回到刚才，开始Clean the deck。大家一点一点的去改进，
trying to improve a little bit.
就会有一个新的理解。
but before that.
稍等，我看有人有问题。
(You have typo in 63.) We have typo in 63? Yeah yeah, it's for sure, for sure. It's really a legacy code.
（你63行有个拼写错误。） 63行有个错？哦对，没错。这就是遗留代码啊。
But you notice something wrong? We'll fix that.
不过你注意到了没有这里有点问题？我们得修复它。
It's red.
这红了。
It's difficult to
如果我们代码红了，
be confident if my code is red because if I made
我很难有信心去修改它。因为如果
a mistake,
改的时候出错了，
I don't see the mistake. I prefer to see green
我根本不知道出错了。我还是更喜欢看到这里的代码
in my tool. So
都是绿色的。
to do that,
为了让它变绿，
we'll completely ignore the test and just search the bug.
我们要完全忽略这个测试，先去找bug。
It's a good technique
这是一个很好的技巧
if you're in the same situation when the test is failing,
如果你也面临着测试挂了的这种情况，
and you need to refactor just before fixing the bug
你需要先重构再修bug，
you ignore that test and just search the bug.
你最好就先忽略那个测试。
So that it's green you have a test on this. You refactor and then you enable back the test to fix the bug.
现在变绿了，我们这也还有一个测试。我们可以先重构，然后启用这个测试，再去修复bug。
So this is what
这其实就是
you're doing. And white
你现在做的。白色
is meaning we don't run the test. And now I'm ready. (Fast question. Does it look better to
意味着我们不跑这个测试。现在我就可以开始了。（我有个问题。如果我们
create a test, which test the
新建一个测试，来测试当前的行为，
current behavior,
是不是更好？
because when your refactoring, you want to basically
因为当你重构的时候，你还是想
maintain the current behaviour.) Yeah.
保留当前的行为的。）是的。
(So by creating a new test, so that ignore the old test.) Absolutely. (By creating a new test which test the
（新建一个测试的话，我们忽略掉旧的测试。）没错。（新建的测试就测
current behaviour, you can't basically break it.)
当前的行为，我们得通过这个新测试才行。）
Yeah. That is a technique I like a lot which is a golden master.
是的，这是Golden master，是我很喜欢的一个技巧。
Golden master is you take a legacy code,
Golden master是你拿到一个遗留代码，
you clone it,
复制这个代码，
and you write acceptance tests.
然后去写验收测试。
Every time I send that input into the legacy code and the new instance, which is the one I will work on,
每当我将输入发送到遗留代码和新写的代码时，
I'm expecting to see the same output
我得到的两个输出
on both instances.
应该一样。
So that without
所以即使
even understanding the legacy,
不知道代码的上下文，
I can have a test on this.
我依然可以有这个测试。
Making me and forcing me... I don't break any existing behavior.
这也强迫我，不要影响现有的行为。
So this is a strategy that we could have done. But here we are implementing the business rule
我们本来应该这么做的，不过现在我们在实现业务准则，
as a domain expertise.
所以作为领域专家，
So we will stick to that point for now. But it's a good way for refactor.
我们就先用现有的代码。不过你说的那个确实是重构的好方法。
Just clean the deck Bruno.
Bruno，继续clean the deck吧。
The first variable,
我们可以看到，
this is as noticeable, the variable seat.
这第一个变量，seat。
I'll just have a look
我要看一下
where is used. Far from the usage. Yeah, far.
在哪用了它。离调用的地方很远啊。是啊，确实远。
So
那...
maybe,
也许
I can decide to move this one
我可以把它移的
close to the usage.
离调用的地方近一点的。
Here for example. In the back of the room can you see all the code?
比如放这。后面的人你们看得到所有的代码吗？
Because my test is running in real time I know I'm not breaking the code. It's still green.
我的测试是实时运行的，所以我知道我没有破坏现有的代码。这都是绿色的。
The behavior of the C programmer, because I was a C programmer, was to put
我是个C语言程序员，C语言的程序员一般习惯
all the variable at the beginning of the code.
把所有变量都写在代码的最前面。
So this is your...?
所以这是你写的代码？
No it's not mine. Ok, second one is count.
不，不是我写的。好，第二个变量是count。
Count, so... What a name.
count，这名字起的。
Yeah, count, wow.
是啊，count。
What a stupid loop. Yeah, we're looping on the list.
这又是个愚蠢的循环。是啊，我们在list里循环。
Actually it's a list of property count.
这其实是count的list。
It's exactly the same number.
完全是一样的数字啊。
We have a hint here. It's unused. Maybe ??? developer want to say something?
这有个提示，这个没被用过。它是不是想告诉我们点什么？
So what I can do is maybe to use
我应该可以用
availabelSeats.
availabelSeats
And apply count property.
赋值给count。
Yeah because at the end of the for each loop, count will have the same
对，因为这个循环最后，count和availableSeats的值
value as availableSeats. I can remove this one.
是一样的。我现在可以删了这个。
Okay?
好了。
Cool, I'll leave it.
好，就先这样。
On this screen hight, do we have ah...before we...We can check.
现在，我们可以看一下，这方法占几个屏幕。
One, two.
一，二
Two
两个
Two and a half? Two and a half, yeah.
两个半？对，两个半。
So that was another thing that bother me to have a method like that.
这其实也是另一个困扰我的事情，方法太长了。
Ok.
好吧。
Ok, this is a code for the train topology.
好，这是火车拓扑的代码。
Maybe we can rename it?
没准我们可以重命名？
Yeah. Ok?
可以啊。
Train topology?
Yeah that' fine.
嗯可以。
Traintopol and you can...Topology is better. That may explain we were talking about
Traintopol然后...拓扑这个词挺好，我们刚才一直都在说
the  train topology. So that's better. Okay, trainInst.
火车拓扑嘛。对，确实比之前那个好。那这个词，trainInst。
Instruction? Instance?
指令？还是实例？
We asked domain expert about that, he said no I'm not aware of train instance by domain. So,
我们问了领域专家，他说领域里没有火车实例的概念。
should be train install maybe or. So let's treat its name into train. Yeah. So you install a train from a trainTopology ok? Yeah.
所以这个可能是train install？那我把它改成train吧。所以现在我们从火车拓扑，得到一个火车。不错。
What is this guy?
这是什么？
numberOfReserv. Maybe you can just...
numberOfReserv。也许你应该
Put it here for people in the back to see everything. Ok. You see this one?
把它放这边，这样后面的人能看清所有的代码。好的，你们看这个。
numberOfReserv. Is it used? Yeah.
numberOfReserv。这个被用过吗？没有吧？。
It's a pattern actually.
这就是个形式而已啊。
We use a variable
我们这个变量
for nothing and... Just in case the calculation, that count is wrong maybe you can have a...
没有什么用。只是为了计算，以防我们的计数是错的。
Maybe that's intends? I don't know.
也许这个是故意的？我也不知道。
Some times we don't have to try to understand. This is just silly stuff.
我们其实不用去理解这个。这些乱七八糟的。
Ok, so I can remove this one.
好，我可以把这个删了。
Ok so you get rid of it. Yeah I get rid of this one.
那你不要这个了？对不要了。
Ok you can delete it.
那你可以删了它。
Yeah.
是的。
Maybe...Each is？ Each...
呃...这个each
It's seat. Yes, from collection of Seats, we get a seat.
应该是seat。对，从seat的collection中我们得到的是seat。
This is a typo. reservedSet.
这有个小错误，应该是reservedSet。
We don't talk about set. We've asked the domain expert also, do we even have set? They said no. This is a loop too.
我们没有集合的概念。我们问过领域专家到底有没有集合的概念？他们说没有。这又有一个循环。
But never used.
但是没被用过。
Who has already seen that kind of
谁之前也在代码里遇见过这种
variables, declarations in the code not even used anymore
根本没被用过的变量、声明之类的？
Yeah. Legacy code is full of
对。遗留代码里
this kind of stuff.
很多这种东西。
And it's kind of polluting our mind.
这有点污染我们的头脑。
This one.
这个。
Have a look at this one. We have
看看这个。我们这有
a if here. And we have pretty much the same if at the invest?
一个if。然后我们在这又有一个差不多的if。
Yeah I'll just...
是，那我...
We like symmetry it's much better to compare stuff. To do so, as we suggested, to invest? Yeah, it's a good a idea.
我们喜欢对称性，这有利于我们去相互比较。为了这么做，我们建议把第一个if逻辑反转一下。对这是个好主意。
Indent, invest if, and then,
反转这个if逻辑。然后
ok we can see pretty much the same...
你看这些都差不多一样...
I will select...No, no, wait.
我要选中...等一下
Just illustrate it.
我们看一下。
Here, as you can see there is one if. Here.
这，你看有一个if。这里。
And pretty much the same here.
这又有一个差不多的。
So the idea is since there is nothing in the middle we can cut the code into the if below.
因为中间什么也没有，我们可以把下面if里的代码剪切，
And put it into the end of the first if.
粘贴到第一个if到后面。
This one, just at the end, to respect the algorithm.
这个，就在它后面，这样也符合算法逻辑。
So
然后
it will simplify a little bit the code structure also.
这也会简化一点代码结构。
It's really great. Green yeah. Okay?
这确实不错。都是绿的你看。
So now you can...Read
现在我们可以...看一下
Why are you doing that? Because... It's white. Yeah. Entrnce?, when the code
你为什么那么做？因为，它是白色的。对，当代码
is not covered,
没被覆盖，
put a white
这会有一个白色的
indicator.
标识符
It's a
这对我们来说
good for us. This one is not necessary too.
挺好的。这个也没有什么必要。
Ok, you can remove some lines.
对你可以把这几行删了。
So I think we...
我觉得我们
have some space? Yeah maybe this one can be closer to the usage.
有些空行？对，也许这个可以离用它的地方更近一点。
Ok.
好
Ok so you
好，你现在
closer the declaration to the usage. And it's not perfect, but
把声明和调用放一起了。目前还不完美，但是
we changed a little bit.
我们至少做了一些改变。
Not so much. It's not really a deep refactory. It's just to be more confident.
改的不多。这不是一个完全的重构。这只是让我们更自信。
It's the first round, the first pass on the code,
如果我们想完善心理模型，
when improving our mental model about it
并清理一下代码，
and trying to clean up some mess.
这只是第一步。